这是资阳市二零二四年初中学业水平考试暨高中阶段学校招生考试英语听力理解部分。该部分。分为第一、第二两节。注意，回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间，将你的答案转涂到答题卡上。请看听力理解部分第一节第一节，听下面五段对话。每段对话后有一个小题，从题中所给的
B Sorry, I won't do it again.
三个选项中选出与其意思相符的图片，并标在试卷的。相应位置。听每段对话前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。听完每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。每段对话仅读一遍。现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读第一小题的有关内容。
Text 2 I made the same mistake in the exam.
What should I do?
Peter, you can talk to your teacher for advice.
Text 3 Let's go swimming this evening, Kate.
That's a good idea.
Text 4 I'm not feeling well with my stomach.
Please lie down.
Let me have a check.
Text 5 Gina, what's the weather like tomorrow?
Cold and rainy, so you should take your umbrella and coat.
第一节到此结束。
of I can help more people.
第二节。听下面五段对话或独白，每段对话或独白后有几个小题，从题中所给的三个选项中选出最佳选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。听每段对话。对话或独白前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。每段对话或独白读两遍听下面一段对话，回答第六至第七小题。现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
What's your dream job?
I'd like to be a teacher.
I want to teach in poor village.
I watched a movie about a village school teacher yesterday.
It's very good.
So, that's why you want to be a teacher?
Yes, I think many children need our help.
Why do you want to be a policeman?
I think it's a dangerous job.
Because I can help more people.
What's your dream job?
I'd like to be a teacher.
I want to teach in poor village.
I watched a movie about a village school teacher yesterday.
It's very good.
So, that's why you want to be a teacher?
Yes, I think many children need our help.
听下面一段对话，回答第八至第十小题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Hello, may I speak to Sue?
No, she is out.
This is Rose, Sue's sister.
What's up? This is Perry speaking.
I have a good news to tell you.
Last week we had a competition for all young inventors.
Sue invented a robot that can teach people English.
It won the top prize.
Really? That's great.
Then, can you tell us her age and address?
OK, she is fifteen years old and we live at number forty Bay High Road.
Thank you. The prize will be sent to your home by next weekend.
That's great. I'll tell her.
Hello, may I speak to Sue?
No, she is out.
This is Rose, Sue's sister.
What's up? This is Perry speaking.
I have a good news to tell you.
Last week we had a competition for all young inventors.
Sue invented a robot that can teach people English.
It won the top prize.
Really? That's great.
Then, can you tell us her age and address?
OK, she is fifteen years old and we live at number forty Bay High Road.
Thank you. The prize will be sent to your home by next weekend.
That's great. I'll tell her.
听下面一段对话，回答第十一至第十三小题。现在你。有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题
Thank you. Oh, there is a jacket on the ground.
Whose is this, Mike?
It must belong to John.
He played basketball here just now.
Let me see.
It can't be John's.
Why? It's much too large for him.
Then it might belong to Henry.
He played basketball with John.
Henry? Oh, it might belong to him.
I remember. He has a white jacket.
Yes, it's Henry's.
His ID card is in the pocket.
Let's take it to him.
Good idea. Oh, there is a jacket on the ground.
Whose is this, Mike?
It must belong to John.
He played basketball here just now.
Let me see.
It can't be John's.
Why? It's much too large for him.
Then it might belong to Henry.
He played basketball with John.
Henry? Oh, it might belong to him.
I remember. He has a white jacket.
Yes, it's Henry's.
His ID card is in the pocket.
Let's take it to him.
Good idea. Text 9.
听下面一段对话，回答第十四至第十六小题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
Excuse me, I'd like to go to the bird nest.
Okay. Welcome to take my taxi.
Here we go.
Thanks. How soon will we get there?
In about 15 minutes.
Is this your first time here?
Yes. How do you like our city?
I like it.
It's big and beautiful.
There are many places of interest to visit.
But some places are too crowded.
Yes. The traffic is bad, especially when people finish work.
So, why do you prefer to take a taxi?
Because I think it's faster and better than the bus.
Besides, I like taking photos on the way.
That's a good choice.
We will be there soon.
Excuse me, I'd like to go to the bird nest.
Okay. Welcome to take my taxi.
Here we go.
Thanks. How soon will we get there?
In about 15 minutes.
Is this your first time here?
Yes. How do you like our city?
I like it.
It's big and beautiful.
There are many places of interest to visit.
But some places are too crowded.
Yes. The traffic is bad, especially when people finish work.
So, why do you prefer to take a taxi?
Because I think it's faster and better than the bus.
Besides, I like taking photos on the way.
That's a good choice.
We will be there soon.
听下面一段独白，回答第十七至第二十小题。现在你有二十秒钟的时间阅读这四个小题。
Text 10 Hello, Wongfeng.
This is called you, but there was no answer.
So, I have to leave a message.
I plan to return to Japan in July.
But I have to leave right now, because there was a terrible earthquake in my
hometown this morning.
I'm really worried about my family.
We planned to play ping -pong this weekend, but I can't make it.
What a pity.
I'm so happy to be with you these days.
You're so active, and you can always bring me so much happiness.
Thank you so much for helping me with my poor Chinese.
It's hard to say goodbye, but I have to.
I'm at the airport, and my flight is leaving.
I think I will visit China again, and we can meet soon.
See you. Text Wongfeng.
This is I called you, but there was no answer.
So, I have to leave a message.
I plan to return to Japan in July.
But I have to leave right now, because there was a terrible earthquake in my
hometown this morning.
I'm really worried about my family.
planned to play ping -pong this weekend, but I can't make it.
What a pity.
I'm so happy to be with you these days.
You're so active, and you can always bring me so much happiness.
Thank you so much for helping me with my poor Chinese.
It's hard to say goodbye, but I have to.
I'm at the airport, and my flight is leaving.
I think I will visit China again, and we can meet soon.
See you. Thank you for watching.
第二节到此结束。现在你有两分钟。时间，将试卷上的答案转涂到答题卡上。
Thank you for watching.
you watching. for Thank you for watching.
听力理解部分到此结束
Thank you you watching.